PURVI PATEL

Barrie, ON | +1 (705) 817 9476

purvi98patel@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/purvipatel98/

Objective

Highly skilled and motivated Junior Cybersecurity Analyst with over 2+ years of experience in information security, risk assessments, and internal audits. Seeking for a opportunity, which will enable me to utilize the training received in my course in real world complex situations.

Skills

- Specialized in TCP/IP, OSI model, and network protocols such as DNS, SMTP, HTTP, FTP.
- Utilized Microsoft office applications such as Outlook, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Visio.
- Adapted and excelled in compliance audits, familiar with ISO 27001, SSAE18 SOC1-3, CIS Controls, PCI
- Proficiently adhered in network investigation, event analysis, escalation procedures, and reporting.
- Coordinated risk assessments, conducted network monitoring, troubleshooting, and configurations.
- Implemented and managed various Anti-Virus, Firewall, OSI Layer, and information security.

Education

Artificial Intelligence Certificate (Honors) - Georgian College, Barrie ON	2024
Information Systems Security Certificate (Honors) - Georgian College, Barrie ON	2023
B.Sc. in Information Technology - Uka Tarsadia University, Gujarat, IN	2020

Experience

Client Service Associate- Walmart, Barrie ON

2022 - Present

- Nurture customer service expertise, fostering positive interactions, and resolving issues promptly.
- Guide the sales team of 10, achieving a 25% increase in sales targets over two consecutive quarters.
- Influence a marketing strategy that increases customer engagement by 30%, enhancing 15% sales.
- Showcase attention to keen detail and ability to maintain confidentiality.

Network Link - Entrepreneur

2023 - Present

- Fortified cybersecurity with 30% vulnerability reduction in network infrastructure solutions.
- Crafted groundbreaking approaches, resulting in a 25% reduction in cybersecurity incidents.
- Navigated dynamic landscapes, achieving a 20% increase in cybersecurity resilience.
- Proficient in network technologies, routers, WAN link, domain controller, LAN, and wireless network.

Cyber Security Analyst - Cyber Infotech, Surat IN

2020 - 2023

- Developed a deep understanding of threats through continuous monitoring, totaling 150+ incidents.
- Identified and patched 95% of vulnerabilities, performed forensic analyst, and log file analysis.
- Utilized Nessus for vulnerability scanning, leading to a 15% reduction in system vulnerabilities.
- Implemented IDS like Snort, achieving a 20% increase in threat detection accuracy.
- Deployed technologies like Burp Suite, and SIEM (McAfee, Splunk).

Certifications

Certified Identity and Access Manager (CIAM)
Palo Alto Networks Certified Cybersecurity Associate (PCCSA)